The Lugansk Regional Council didn’t make
Луганский областной Совет да не принимал
any decisions about which LPR LPR who
никаких решений про какие лнр лнр кто
declared the LPR wait you, you
объявил лнр подожди ты ты по ты
understand that this is
понимаешь что это
nonsense
бред
Hello Hello I’m from the city of
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsk
Хмельницке Вы
Where are you from excellent I’m from Lugansk exactly from
откуда отлично Я с Луганска именно с
Lugansk itself what from Lugansk itself think
Луганска что с самого Луганска прикиньте
Super class class Generally cool  yes, it’s
Класс супер типа Вообще круто да вот
interesting, as I understand it, you
интересно я так понимаю что вы в
lived in Lugansk in 1914
четырнадцатом году жили в Луганске
Yes, it’s absolutely super you can say
Да совершенно верно супер можете сказать
look, I’m just a zhur I’m a journalist, I’m writing
смотрите Я просто жур Я журналист я пишу
a book about the events of 1414, yes
книгу о событиях четырнадцатого года да
You can remember That’s all for me in Ukraine I
Можете вспомнить Вот мне все в Украине Я
say that it’s like there’s a militia there And so
говорю что вроде как там ополчение И так
then Russia, like, didn’t do anything, yes And they
дальше Россия типа ничего не делала да А
tell me that look, Girkin
мне говорят что смотрите вот гиркин
started the invasion, like his team in the
да начал вторжение типа его команда на
Donbass on April 12, and I don’t know, I don’t know
Донбасс 12 апреля а я не знаю не знаю
Girkin, no, no, and then Donetsk Yes,
гиркина нене е е и тогда Донецк Да да
yes, and all the Ukrainians tell me that Don
вот и мне все украинцы говорят что Дон
is Donets Yes  that before this type there
это Донец Да что до этого типа никаких
were no military operations in the Donbass, yes.
боевых действий на Донбассе не было да
Can you remember when you had military
Можете вспомнить когда у вас были боевые
operations in the Donbass? Were there any
действия на Донбассе Были ли до 12
Girkin before April 12 - this is the Donets, here we are
апреля гиркин - это Донец вот мы
Lugansk People's Republic I'm asking Just before
Луганская народна Я спрашиваю Просто до
April 12 of this
12 апреля
year there were actions before April 12 of which
года были увы действия до 12 апреля чего
year  until April 14th Well, I don’t
года до 14 апреля Ну я не
remember April 14th Let’s say until
помню апреля 14 года Давай до
the fourteenth year let’s say until what
четырнадцатого года давай так до чего
year Yes until the fourteenth year
года да до четырнадцатого года
Let’s not until the fourteenth year No so
Давай нет до четырнадцатого года Нет так
in the fourteenth year when your
в четырнадцатом году когда у вас боевые
hostilities began in Lugansk or in the
действия начались в Луганске или в
region Well, I didn’t note the dates  listen
области Ну я под датам не засека слушай
for 10 years already no wait stop you
уже 10 лет не ну подожди стоп ты же
remembered When did you first feel the
вспомнил Когда ты первый раз ощутил
combat action it’s a shock for example the
боевые дейст это шок например
entire entire LPR should know and remember this
вся вся лнр должна знать и помнить этот
day
день
Well I remember the events that happened
Ну я помню события которые происходили
Why do I need a day No well a month at least a month
Зачем мне день Не ну месяц хотя бы месяц
you can
можете
remember Why do I need a month  What are the
вспомнить Зачем мне месяц гово пом
events on the Maidan? I remember how we
события на Майдане Помню как мы
watched the
наблюдали за
Maidan.
майданом
How the demoniacs are not there. Maidan is
Как бесноватые там нет так Майдан - это
not military action. Yes, what kind of events in
не военные действия Да вот Какие в
Lugansk? Were there Ukrainian tanks there?
лугански Были ли там танки украинские
For example, there was something like this. I
заезжали например было
mean, Lugansk - It was Ukraine
такое В смысле Луганск - Это был Украина
until the fourteenth
до четырнадцатого
year. Heard no Yes, audible  I hear I’m
года Слышно нет Дада слышно слышно я тут
describing here, yes, that’s correct, in
описываю да то правильно то в
1414 there were some
четырнадцатом году были какие-то там
tanks there that entered Lugansk, something else
танки заходили в Луганск что-то ещё
was
такое было
interesting, they were here for something, the
интересно так они здесь были при чём-то
Ukrainian army was standing here, and No,
украинская армия стояла здесь причём Не
well, the Ukrainian army entered Lugansk
ну украинская армия там зашла в Луганск
there Bombed  Lugansk maybe this was the case or
там Бомбила Луганск может было такое или
not, well, a little closer to the context, I
нет ну ближе немножко к контексту я
understand something, well, look. Maybe you
понимаю что-то ну вот смотрите Может
can tell me, for example, it seems like
может подскажете например вот вроде как
some kind of Lugansk People’s
бы какая-то Луганская народная
Republic. And who and when organized the
республика А кто и когда организовал
Lugansk People’s
луганскую народную
Republic
Республику
? Well, I don’t remember the dates. In what year  we
А ну в датах не помню В чем году мы
disconnected yes nene And who
отсоединили да нене А кто
who look you had For example, I remember
кто смотрите у вас было Например я помню
that in Lugansk there was a Lugansk Regional
что в Луганске был Луганский областной
Council of deputies elected by all residents of the Lugansk
Совет депутаты избранные всеми жителями
region there was
Луганской области было
such a thing residents of Lugansk come on so let’s live Speak
такое жители Луганска давай так давай
More than once again there
жите Говори Не ещё раз сри
was a Lugansk Regional Council and there was a
были Луганский областной Совет да был
head of the regional council deputies
глава областного совета депутаты
elected all by all residents of the Lugansk
избранные все всеми жителями Луганской
region
области
So wait, they were in the fourteenth year
Так подожди были в четырнадцатом году
when Yanukovych was overthrown elected
когда свергли Януковича избранные в се
again once again look don’t run away don’t
ещё раз ещё раз смотри не убегай не
run away look look again look
убегай смотри смотри ещё раз смотри
Lugansk don’t run away those question
Луганский не убегай те вопрос вопрос
I’m asking the Lugansk Regional Council and didn’t
задаю Луганский областной Совет да не
make any decisions about which LPR
принимал никаких решений про какие лнр
LPR who declared the LPR wait you pony
лнр кто объявил лнр подожди ты ты пони
You understand that this is nonsense who took
Ты понимаешь что это бред кто принял
[ __ ] people into power in Ukraine in
[__] людей во власть в Украине в
1914 who brought Poroshenko I’m
четырнадцатом году кто привёл Порошенко
there it’s the Americans it’s the Americans everything is
я там это американцы это американцы всё
clear yes the Americans Americans Nuland
понятно да американцы Американцы нуланд
and that’s it A And who in the LPR who proclaimed the LPR
и всё А А кто в лнр кто провозгласил лнр
and
и
when residents residents live when when
когда жители жители жите когда когда
how many of these residents When on what day
сколько этих жителей Когда в какой день
You look You look you understand the self-
Ты смотри Ты смотри понимаешь само
proclaimed republic the most
провозглашён ная республика самая
proclaimed republic
провозглашён ная республика
of when
у когда были нарушены
our when our
наши когда были нарушены наши
constitutional rights were violated and what rights the conci chose
конституционные права да какие права
Well, I mean, would
конци Ну в смысле выговорил б
you reprimand on
ты на
reprimands
выговаривает
constitutionally
конституционно
handsome sri &amp;
красавчик сри пож
legends of the people's
сказания народной
Republic Yes, [ __ ] you on dates with
Республики Да нахуй ты мне на датах с
wait Well, look we are in Ukraine We
подожди Ну смотри мы в Украине У нас
also left the USSR Yes I don’t Yes I don’t Yes
тоже мы вышли из СССР Да я не Да я не Да
I don’t remember [ __ ] When is my
я не помню [__] Когда у меня день
birthday What are you telling me Yeah Well
рождения Что ты мне рассказываешь Ага Ну
look  Here I am, for example, here in
смотри вот я я например у нас например в
Ukraine, for example, everyone says Ukraine
Украине все говорят Украина
declared independence The Verkhovna
провозгласила независимость Верховная
Rada of the Ukrainian Soviet
Рада украинской Советской
Socialist Republic
Социалистической Республики
declared independence on August 24,
провозгласила независимость 24 августа
1991 and we know Which body Yes, the
1991 года и мы знаем Какой орган Да
Supreme Rada of the Ukrainian Socialist Republic Yes proclaimed and on
верховный рада урср Да провозгласила и
what date Which body do you have and when did it
какого числа Какой орган у вас и когда
proclaim the Lugansk People's
провозгласил луганскую народную
Republic
Республику
y Listen, yes You have a computer at your fingertips,
у Слушай да У тебя компьютер под рукой
that’s where I know Listen, we go
там я откуда знаю Слушай
to the toilet, we generally Russians go to the
у в туалет мы мы вообще россияне в
toilet on the street
туалет на улице
AK here is the act of proclamation, the act of
ходим АК вот акт провозглашения акт
proclamation of the Lugansk People’s
провозглашение Луганской народной
Republic when a new
Республики когда появляется новое
state appears Yes There is an act of proclamation
государство Да Есть акт провозглашения
of Independence where is the act of proclamation
Независимости где акт провозглашение
of Independence Yes no no  there is
Независимости Да нету нету такого вот
no such thing Yes, Google will help you,
нету Вот именно те Да Google тебе в помо
really, look, I’ve been googling, I’ve been googling for 10 years, they’ve been
ну реально смотри я гуглил я 10 лет
bombing the Donbass for 10 years,
гуглил там уже всё 10 лет бомбят Донбасс
and I’m googling to find this act and
А я гуглю чтобы этот акт найти и
stop this bombing, but no, you know,
остановить эту бомбёжку а нету понимаешь
this act doesn’t exist in the sense of 10 years 10 10  They've been
нету этого акта по смысле 10 лет 10 10
bombing the Donbass for years now and they've been sleeping for
лет уже бомбят Донбасс и уже двадцать
twenty years
чет год
already. They've been bombing the Donbass for 10
проспись 10 лет уже бомбят Донбасс 10
years. They'd just show it for 10 years. There's an Act of
лет просто показали бы вот Есть акт
Proclamation of Independence, a law. And that's it. And they
провозглашение Независимости закон И всё
stopped bombing the Donbass. And it
И перестали бомбить Донбасс А так
turns out that no one declared
получается что никто не провозглашал
any
никакую
independence, as they showed you; we've
независимость как вам показывали нас
even been recognized by the res who  proclaimed
признали уже даже рес кто провозгласил
tell me who, for example, the regional Council who
скажи кто например областной Совет кто
proclaimed Which body proclaimed Well,
провозгласил Какой орган провозгласил Ну
wait I'm you I'm you damn this same
подожди Я те я те блин этот самый
consultant [ __ ]
консультант бля на
parliamentarian I don't know Well I don't know everyone
парламентарий не зна Ну я не знаю каждый
look everyone for example American USA
смотри каждый например американец США
knows
знает
who recognized the countries we were recognized by the countries
кто признали страны нас признали страны
[ __ ] recognized us [ __ ] Republic
бля нас признали [__] Республики
recognized  and what the [ __ ] are you just trying
признали и ты что бля просто хочешь
to say that they are so strong and recognized okay,
сказать что они так вли и признали ладно
look Mikhail Matveev, you are in
смотри Михаил Матвеев ты Неге
peace like me,
помири как и мне
we are like one Come on, let's
года Мы вроде одного Дава давай
calm down, let's be calmer,
спокойней Да давай спокойней Смотри вот
look, let's look, it turns out that when they
давай смотри получается что вот я когда
proclaim a new state, I
провозглашают новое государство да
have to proclaim some kind of -  it’s a supreme body or
должен провозгласить какой-то орган или
council or that who proclaimed the
совет верховный или что кто провозгласил
LPR Well, you’re beating me on dates and
лнр Ну ты меня по датам бьёшь и по этим
where the
нахрен откуда Ты откуда ты знаешь что
hell do you
мнение своих друзей как бы все У вас
come from?
есть Конституция лнр Конституция лнр
Yes, we are already in Russia, what wait, well,
есть Да мы уже в России какая подожди ну
before before Russia it was also in the Constitution, it
а до до России было тоже в Конституции
should have been written there about the
там же должно было быть написано про
proclamation of who is there When, in short,
провозглашение кто там Когда что короче
you had a legal power Constitution of the LPR
правовая держава у вас была Конституция
If you are a state Well, for sure, probably certainly
лнр Если вы государство Ну наверняка
certainly would have been for
навер наверняка бы наверняка было
sure That is, you  you don’t know, you’ve
наверняка То есть вы не знаете вы не
never seen the Constitution of the
видели никогда Конституцию
LPR Yes, I don’t really care honestly, it’s cool, I just understood
лнр Да мне вообще пофиг честно прикольно
Well, look, you start
просто Ну смотри ты мне ты мне начинаешь
telling me something there,
там что-то рассказы
knowing an interesting question, as a resident of the LPR,
зна интересный вопрос вот как жителю лнр
I correctly understand that the DPR and the LPR
я правильно понимаю что вот ДНР и лнр -
were different states,
это разные государства были
yes Well  in general, yes, that is, these are different
да Ну вообще да то есть это разные
peoples of the DPR, Chinese, these are different peoples.
народы ДНР ский нский это разные народы
Yes, no. What does that have to do with wait, what does the
Да не Это причём подожди причём
State have to do with the Republic?
объявили свою страну ДНР это две разные
Yes, you have a border, you
страны ж было да у вас граница у вас
had customs between the LPR of the
таможня же была между лнр
public, you didn’t have you weren’t a
публики у вас была не у вас была не вы
country, you said that you were recognized by
страна вы сказали что вас признали
other countries, you
другие страны вы
said a republic, this is a form of
сказали республика это фо это Форма
government like a republic, a monarchy,
правления типа вот республика монархия
yes, you were a state. Yes, that’s
да у вас вы были государством Да вот
why  here in Ukraine there were no borders
почему вот при Украине не было границ
n
н
inni, well, citizens voted separately For
инни ну граждане отдельно голосовали За
this they voted For
это голосовали За
theirs Why is it that they made customs
сво Почему получается сделали таможню
between Donetsk and
между Донецком и
Lugansk Well, some kind of controls between
Луганском Ну какие-то контроли между
Ukraine and
Украиной и
Poland Yes, you are different peoples, you are allies But
Польшей Да разные народы вы союзники А у
we have different Republics, I understand But look, here you are
нас разные Республики понял А смотрите А
Since I understood correctly, I understand correctly
вот жеве Раз понял я правильно понимаю
that these are different Republics, different peoples.
что это разные Республики разные народы
Therefore, yes, yes, what do the people have to do with
Поэтому да Да причем вот Какие народы
Naro? Well, how do you look? The
причем Наро Ну как смотри Вот в
Tatars live in the Republic of Tatarstan. Yes, in the
республике Татарстан живут татары Да в
Republic of Adygea there are Adygeans. Yes, the Adygs
Республике там Адыгея адыгейцы Да Адыги
in the Republic of Lugandon there are Lugandon sy. Yes, for
в Республике лугандон там лугандон сы Да
example, that’s what kind of
например вот вы какой
nationality you are in  Ukrainian ass and Ukrainian ass
народность в украино жопе и украино жопе
Well, you are a representative of what nationality
Ну вы Вы представитель какой народности
next No, well, we will continue further Well, let's
дальше Не ну мы дальше мы дальше будем
go to the st in the country of LPR What kind of people
Ну давайте в ст в стране лнр Какой народ
live What nation is already LPR well, that's what kind of
живёт Какая нация уже лнр ну вот какая
nation lived in LPR Russia is in LPR What
нация в лнр жила Россия есть в лнр Какая
nation is living Russia Well what  the nation in the LPR
нация жилая Россия Ну какая нация в лнр
lived in Kazakhstan, the Kazakhs in Ukraine, the
жила в Казахстане казахи в Украине
Ukrainians And in the LPR what was the nation
украинцы А в лнр как нация
called the Russians b Well, what were the Russians
называлась россияне б Ну как россияне
if the LPR was not in Russia What were the
если лнр не было в России Как назывались
people called the population of the LPR Are you where are you born where did
люди население лнр Ты где Ты где родился
you have a passport Which is more correct again
у тебя паспорт Какой это вернее ещё раз
Well, you proclaimed  lnr what is
Ну вот вы вы провозгласили лнр что у
written on your certificate You proclaimed
тебя написано Вы провозгласили
lnr in the certificate the Ukrainian Soviet
лнр в свидетельстве украинская Советская
Socialist Republic
Социалистическая Республика
is written USSR Yes no not the USSR I don’t have it
написано СССР Да не не СССР У меня
written Soviet Union But mine
написано не Союз Советский А у меня
says
написано
wait you in the next year of the year in the first
подожди ты во вго года года во перго
year Yes it says place of
года да написано место
birth Open look open open
рождения Открой смотри открой открой
your certificate at  you are written RSFSR
своё свидетельство у тебя написано РСФСР
or there is
или там
URSR for
урср за
look at the passport, the passport you
по смотри паспорт паспорт паспорт вы
gave was from the USSR and the
давали сссровский а свидетельство о
birth certificate was written like place of birth
рождении писали типа место рождения
URSR
урср
Ukrainian Radyanskoe And what they wrote there is
украинско радянское А что там написали
already damn it You know how on the fence, too, to
то уже блин Знаешь как на заборе тоже до
see Come on, I still can’t understand for
смот Давай всё-таки я не могу понять для
me  The key question is how the
меня Ключевой вопрос чем отличалась
Donetsk nation and the Lugansk nation differed. I
нация Донецкая и нация Луганская Я
’ll try. I’ll try. I’ll try
попробую Я попробую Попробую тебе
to tell you. What’s the difference between the Donetsk nation
рассказать Чем отличается нация Донецкая
and the
и нация
Lugansk nation. There was no nation. Well, what was the
Луганская не было нации Ну как
state like? That means
государство было значит
it would have
бы это
been
были
years,
года
but what are you talking about? God, I don’t
н что ж ты точишь в какой Господи я не
understand what you want at all  with this Okay, that's it
пойму что ты хочешь вообще этим Ладно
Misha Matveev, in short, you're already
всё Миша Матвеев меня короче ты уже
sick of me. Let's go for
задолбал Давай идёшь
a walk. It's just unrealistically
гулять Просто нереально
stupid that they created a state. Yes, but I don't know
тупой создали государство Да но не знаю
when, I don't know who. In short, why in
когда не знаю кто короче да почему в
every normal state?
каждом нормальном государстве Да
Yes, they show us Independence Day
показывают вот у нас День независимости
such and such Yes, how independence was accepted
такой-то такой-то Да как принималось
for example, in America Yes,
независимость например в ээ Америке Да
everyone knows that a declaration of independence was adopted there and on the
каждый знает что была принята там
independence of the United States. Yes, who are the
декларация да о независимости США Да кто
founding fathers. Yes, in Ukraine. We also
отцы основатели Да в Украине Мы тоже
know, yes, on August 24,
знаем да 24 августа
1991, who the Supreme Council is, the Verkhovna
1991 года кто Верховный Совет Верховная
Rada of the Ukrainian Soviet
Рада украинской Советской
Socialist Republic
Социалистической Республики
proclaimed and adopted an act of
провозгласила да приняла акт о
independence, that is, there is a body  who
независимости то есть есть орган который
accepted when he accepted it is there In the act the
принял когда принял там стоит В акте
signature of the head of the Verkhovna Rada Kravchuk
подпись главы Верховной Рады кравчука
everything is clear Yes LPR DPR who
всё всё чётко Да лнр ДНР кто
accepted we don’t know when he accepted we don’t
принял не знаем когда принял не
know some kind of act there is no Yes but there is a
знаем акт какой-то есть нет Да но есть
country subscribe to Mi Telegram right
страна подпишись на Mi Telegram прямо
now the axis of wines and
зараз ось вин а
popk tse duzhe and  very politely
попк це дуже и дуже важливо
L
L